The park is gone.
Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by J.A. Bayona.
Three years after Jurassic World was destroyed, Isla Nublar now sits abandoned.
When the island's dormant volcano begins roaring to life, Owen and Claire mount a
campaign to rescue the remaining dinosaurs from this extinction-level event.
Owen Grady, played by Chris Pratt.
Claire Dearing, played by Bryce Dallas Howard.
Eli Mills, played by Rafe Spall.
Franklin Webb, played by Justice Smith.
Zia Rodriguez, played by Daniella Pineda.
Benjamin Lockwood, played by James Cromwell.
Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom is a 2018 American
science fiction action film directed by J.
Bayona and written by Derek Connolly and Colin Trevorrow.
The sequel to Jurassic World (2015), it is the second installment in the Jurassic
World film series and fifth overall of the Jurassic Park franchise.
Chris Pratt, Bryce Dallas Howard, BD Wong, and Jeff Goldblum reprise their roles from previous
films in the series, with Toby Jones, Ted Levine, and Rafe Spall joining the cast.
The story follows Owen Grady and Claire Dearing as they return to the fictional Central American island of Isla Nublar to rescue the remaining
dinosaurs from an impending volcanic eruption, only to discover a mercenary team's ulterior motives to bring them to the US mainland.
Filming took place from February to July 2017 in
the United Kingdom and in Hawaii.
With a production budget of up to $465 million, Fallen Kingdom
is the second-most expensive film ever made.
Fallen Kingdom premiered at the WiZink Center in Madrid on May 21, 2018, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 22, by Universal Pictures.
The film grossed over $1.3 billion worldwide, making it the third Jurassic film to pass the billion-dollar mark, and
was the third-highest-grossing film of 2018 and peaked as the 12th-highest-grossing film of all time.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who generally praised the visuals,
cinematography, music and darker tone, while others criticized the screenplay.
A sequel, titled Jurassic World Dominion, was released on June 10, 2022.
The film explores themes of tyrannosaurus rex, volcano,
rescue mission, sequel, wild animal.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.